ascopubs.org 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy | ASCO

_Last modified: July  31, 2019_

**About this Policy**

ASCO and its affiliates are committed to respecting your privacy. We take privacy, security, and complying with data protection and privacy laws seriously. Our Privacy Policy provides transparency into how we collect, use, share, process, and protect your personal information when you use our products, services, and our websites. In addition to this Privacy Policy, users of our websites should consult the ASCO Website [Terms of Use](https://www.asco.org/about-asco/legal/terms-use) as well as any product specific terms and conditions that may apply. Our Privacy Policy is updated from time to time. If we make a change, then we will post this on our website and send an alert or website pop-up. For example, this version includes changes to improve clarity and transparency, to address requirements under the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) or related regulations, and to clarify your options with respect to tracking technologies. 

We’ve broken this policy down into the following sections, so you can easily find the details you need.

  1. How To Use This Privacy Policy
  2. Who We Are
  3. How This Policy Applies
  4. Who Collects Information
  5. How We Collect Your Information
  6. What We Collect
  7. How We Use Your Information
  8. How We Share Your Information
  9. Keeping Your Personal Information Secure
  10. Your Rights and User Restrictions
  11. How To Contact Us
  12. International Users
  13. Glossary

We hope that reading this Privacy Policy gives you a clear idea of how we manage information about you.  Please carefully review this Privacy Policy.  Note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of the Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

**By using, accessing, or becoming a  Registered User of the Website, or by clicking through an acknowledgement, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, and consent to our collection, use, processing, and disclosure of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.**

**1\. How To Use This Privacy Policy**

In this Privacy Policy, we explain how we collect, use, share, process, and protect your personal information when you use our products, services, and websites.

**2\. Who We Are**

We are American Society of Clinical Oncology, Inc., and its subsidiaries and affiliates, including Conquer Cancer, ASCO Association, CancerLinQ, and QOPI Certification Program: collectively, “ASCO”.

In this Privacy Policy:

  * “we/us/our” means ASCO as described above; and
  * “third party” means someone who is not you or us.

Our registered office is American Society of Clinical Oncology, Inc., 2318 Mill Road, Suite 800, VA, 22314, USA. We are registered in the United States of America with the New York Department of State, Division of Corporations under Registration No. 186471, and with the Virginia State Corporation Commission under SCC ID F12257.

**3\. How this Policy applies**

This Privacy Policy applies to information you provide to us or that we collect automatically:

  * When you visit the Website, including by tracking technologies.
  * Through email, text, other electronic messages, paper registrations, telephone inquiries or communications between you and the Website or ASCO. Note that “Website” is further defined in Section 13, Glossary.
  * When you interact with Website content or applications that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website and that are provided or managed by a third-party (such as the Third Party Managed Pages), if that content or application includes a link to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy does _not_ apply to information:

  * We collect through any other means not referred to above; or
  * Collected through our mobile applications, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and ASCO. Our mobile applications are governed by a separate [Mobile Application Privacy Policy](https://www.asco.org/about-asco/legal/mobile-app-privacy-policy), available when you download each application, e.g., iPlanner.

This Privacy Policy does not supersede the [Terms of Use](https://www.asco.org/about-asco/legal/terms-use) that govern your use of the Website. Any conflict between this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use shall be determined in favor of the Terms of Use. Please read the Terms of Use carefully.

**4.  Who Collects Information **

Subject to this Privacy Policy, the [Terms of Use](https://www.asco.org/about-asco/legal/terms-use), and any other rules or policies applicable to the Website, ASCO and certain third parties collect the information described in this Privacy Policy through the Website. 

_ASCO Pages and Content Managed by Third Parties_

The Website contains certain Third Party Managed Pages hosted, operated, or managed on ASCO’s behalf.  Our contracted third-party service providers may directly collect PII and other information from you as necessary or recommended for completing authorized transactions or other engagements you undertake with ASCO on these pages. Examples of these Third Party Managed Pages include our meeting registration, job search, journals, abstract and manuscript submission sites, volunteer portal, QOPI page, the Cohort Site, PracticeNet, voting pages, shopping cart pages, the ASCO Act Network, myConnection, the ASCO State/Regional Affiliate Program Page, and others.

The Website also makes use of third-party Cookies, Web Beacons, Pixels, and dynamic tags, which may allow third parties to collect information about you and your activities on the Website and provide you, or enable others to provide you, with functionality within our Website, additional personalization, or with advertising.  For additional information concerning Cookies, Web Beacons and Pixels, see Section 13, Glossary.

_Links to External Sites_

Our Website provides external links to other websites to provide those who use the Website with a better, more fulfilling experience. Once you enter another website (whether through an advertisement, service or content link, sponsorship notice, embedded email, or otherwise), be aware that ASCO is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of such other sites (see also [Terms of Use](https://www.asco.org/about-asco/legal/terms-use)). We encourage you to look for and review the privacy statements of each website that you visit from our Website. You should also adjust privacy settings on your Browser or account on any third-party site to match your preferences.

_Third Party Cookies_

Third party websites that you visit from time to time may drop their own Cookies, Web Beacons, Pixels, or other tracking technologies on your browser or device. ASCO is not responsible for the information collected by those third parties or their privacy practices.

**5\. How We Collect Your Information**

We will collect your personal information when you, for example:

  * Buy or use any of our products and services;
  * Use our network or other ASCO products and services;
  * Become an ASCO member;
  * Register for a specific product or service;
  * Subscribe to newsletters, alerts, community forums, or other services from us;
  * Contact us through various channels, or ask for information about an event, publication, product, or service;
  * Take part in a competition, award, grant, or survey;
  * Visit or browse our Website or other ASCO digital properties;
  * Have given permission to other companies to share information about you; or
  * Are the member of a business that we acquire.

We may collect information when such information is available from another public source. We also collect information from certain organizations, where appropriate and to the extent we have legal grounds to do so. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories, billing calculating agencies, and connected network providers.

**6\. What We Collect**

The types of information we may collect depend on the ways in which you engage with ASCO as well as the products and services you elect to receive. This may include, where applicable:

  * Your name, address, phone and/or mobile number, your date of birth, gender, and email address;
  * Your credit or debit card information, information about your bank account and other banking information – for example, we’ll collect the data necessary to process a payment whenever you make a purchase;
  * Your location data. For example, a location is derived from your IP address, geolocation, or other data such as a zip code or name of a town or city;
  * The content of your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our customer service centers, an email sent, or other records of any contact with us;
  * Your account information, such as payment data, subscriptions you use, membership status, meeting attendance, account numbers or other information related to your account.
  * Credential information – we’ll collect passwords, hints, and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services;
  * Your preferences for particular products, services, communications, and lifestyle activities based on how you use our products and services (personalization);
  * See the “Cookies” section for details on what we collect using Cookies, Web Beacons, Pixels, and other technologies, including digital advertising.
  * Your browsing history. Based on your browser and device settings, ASCO may collect the categories of our Websites you have browsed on your device(s), e.g., Research & Progress, Advocacy & Policy, Meetings or Membership, and use these interests to send you personalized marketing or advertising. We may also collect information on the website you were on before and after you visited our Website. You can opt-out of targeted advertising through Cookies and by updating your preference center. See, Section 10, “Your Rights and User Restrictions”.
  * Information we obtain from other sources, such as fraud-prevention agencies, publicly available sites, and from other data providers. This includes demographic data, interest-based data, and internet browsing behavior.

**7\. How We Use Your information**

We use the information you provide to us and the information we collect to improve our products, services, and your experience with the Website. Our use of your information and any communications from you to us will be consistent with the [Terms of Use](https://www.asco.org/about-asco/legal/terms-use) and this Privacy Policy. The information we collect about you and how we collect it varies depending on many factors, including: the products and services that you use and subscribe to, how you have used the products and services, your browser settings, your device, your preference and Cookie settings, and what we have obtained from a third-party with permission to share it with us. ASCO may process your personal data and PII based on:

**A.  ASCO’s _Contract(s)_ with you**. We use your information in connection with our agreements with you. When you place an order online with us, register for a conference, renew your membership, pay your dues electronically, submit materials for publication, or otherwise enter into an e-commerce transaction with us, we collect and transfer to a third-party vendor enough information for us to fulfill these e-commerce transactions, including collecting payment, where applicable. This may include PII and other information required to process payments through payment gateways (e.g. PayPal, Apple Pay).  In addition, by using, accessing, or becoming a Registered User of the Website, or by clicking through an acknowledgement, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, and consent to our collection, use, processing, and disclosure of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Other use cases may include, but are not limited to:

  * Responding to your questions or providing information that you request.
  * Providing you with products, services, or subscriptions you select, including associated benefits.
  * Providing you with account notifications.
  * Managing membership, volunteer, purchase, and registration functions.
  * Carrying out our obligations and enforcing our rights arising from any contracts entered between you and us, including for billing and collection.

**B.  ASCO’s _Legitimate Business Interests_**.  We use your information in connection with ASCO’s legitimate business interests: for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our Website, products, and services.  This also includes use of your Non-Personal Information **(“NPI”) (see  Section 13, Glossary). **The NPI we automatically collect from you is generally used to render, administer, and improve the Website, our services, and our business. It helps us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service. Purposes for which we may use your information include, but are not limited to, the following: 

  * Presenting our Website and its contents to you.
  * Helping dynamically generate content on web pages or in newsletters.
  * Statistically monitoring how many people are using the Website or interacting with communications from us.
  * Tracking generic user behavior.
  * Helping us evaluate the purpose for which our users undertake certain activities, including those listed immediately above.
  * Determining the popularity of certain content.
  * Restricting underage use of our services.
  * Speeding up your searches and facilitating log-in and navigation, including using session timers.
  * Enabling us and our advertisers and social media partners to display advertisements to appropriate target audiences, including through Online Behavioral Advertising.
  * Storing information about your preferences, allowing us to personalize your content.
  * Locating member practices and practice locations for non-members, searching for members in the ASCO Membership Directory and in our Find a Cancer Doctor Database, offering institutional licensing, and for compliance purposes.
  * For other commercially reasonable purposes, including measuring advertising and promotional effectiveness and assessing which areas of the Website to remarket to you after you leave our site.

Also:

  * To advise you of products or services that may be available through ASCO.
  * To notify you about Website maintenance, updates, changes, and new features, including products or services we offer or provide through the Website.
  * To contact you as needed to address a suspected violation of the Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy, or any other rules or policies applicable to the Website.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website.
  * To solicit user feedback to assess user-satisfaction or other needs and interests.
  * To help us in creating new tools, features, and services.

Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they are legitimate, that our use is reasonably necessary for the applicable purpose, and does not materially impact your privacy rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing.  See also, Section 10, “Your rights and User Restrictions”.

**C. Compliance with a Mandatory Legal Obligation**. We use your information in compliance with mandatory legal obligations, including for example accounting and tax requirements, or as may be required by law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organizations, courts or other public authorities, or any other third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement .

**D. Consent**. We use your personal information when you give us consent to do so. When you give your consent for the processing of your personal information, you will be given details on how to change your mind at any time. Consent may be withdrawn or modified **at any time**. Visit Section 10, “Your rights and User Restrictions”  for more information.

**E. Other Potential Uses For Your Personal Information**

In addition to the above use cases, we may lawfully process your personal information for the following purposes:

  1. _Use of Third Party Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies_

The Website makes use of automatic data collection technologies including first and third-party cookies, log files, Web Beacons, Pixels, dynamic tags, and/or other technical means (we refer to these collectively as “ **Cookies** ”), including through Google advertising services. We may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites or other online services to deliver content and advertising tailored to your interests, both on the Website and on third-party websites (including but not limited to search engines and social media websites). This practice is commonly known as “ **Online Behavioral Advertising**.”

The third parties who provide us with third-party Cookies, may use these technologies to collect information about you when you use the Website to provide you with advertising based on your visit to the Website or to collect impressions data regarding the efficacy of advertising placed with us. Third parties may have the ability to link the information they collect about you when you use the Website with other information they collect about you elsewhere on the Internet or information about the device you are using. Third parties may also collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services or mobile devices and may use this information to provide you with Online Behavioral Advertising or other targeted content. 

We encourage you to research and learn about Cookies and other technical means through which information about you may be collected through the websites you visit. See also, Section 7.E and Section 10of this Privacy Policy to learn how you can act to control the use of Cookies on your browser or device.

We currently use a Cookie consent manager, providing you with more transparency about the types of Cookies we place on our website and how they function, and granting you more control over how your data is used. You can update your preferences at any time  here. Please remember that Cookie preferences are browser and device specific, which means that if you use a different browser or device, you will need to set your preferences on that specific browser or device.  ASCO reviews our Cookie consent manager settings on a periodic basis to capture and react to new Cookies and changes in Cookie performance on our Website, so please be aware that any such changes will be reflected in the consent manager on the next available update. Our Cookie consent manager addresses Cookies we place (including third party cookies we place) on our Website – it does not address Cookies that may be placed on your browser or device by third parties unaffiliated with ASCO based on your prior or subsequent browsing history.

Please contact us at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org) should you have any questions or concerns.

  2. _Disclosure of Information to Third-Party Vendors and Service Providers_

ASCO has engaged third-party vendors and service providers to provide services in connection with the Website, outreach for our programs and services, and to help us manage our web presence and improve performance.  We may share personally-identifiable information or “PII” or other information with these third-party vendors and service providers as necessary so that they may provide the services for which they have been engaged. PII and other information submitted to ASCO through Third Party Managed Pages are also shared with the relevant third-party vendor as necessary for completing authorized transactions. For additional information on  “PII” see Section 13, Glossary.

  * In addition, some of the content and services on the Website, including advertisements, are served by third parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and technology and application providers. 
  * Some of our advertisers may participate in the Facebook/Nielsen program, which helps advertisers improve their measurement of advertising effectiveness. If you are a Facebook user and access a page on our site containing an ad from a participating advertiser, you can learn more about this program and find out how to opt out here: <https://www.facebook.com/help/> and here: <http://www.nielsen-online.com/privacy.jsp?section=leg_scs>.  Similar social media platforms or services may have similar programs. You are encouraged to review the privacy practices of your email providers and social media providers.

  3. _Social Networking_

ASCO may maintain a presence on third-party social networking sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Google, YouTube, Instagram, Twitter, and others. ASCO does not control or have responsibility for the collection, tracking, use, or disclosure of your information (including your PII, NPI and Web Information) gathered through these social networking sites, including through the ASCO pages or profiles within those sites, or otherwise because of your participation in social networking sites. Third-party social networking sites may have the ability to link the information they collect about you when you use the Website with other information they collect about you elsewhere on the Internet, including but not limited to your PII, NPI, Website information, or information about the device you are using. Third-party social networking sites and advertisers on these sites, including on the ASCO pages or profiles within these sites, are not obligated to follow or apply this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible social networking provider directly.

  4. _Research and Analytics_

We use a variety of analytics methods including what is commonly referred to as “big data analytics”. Big data analytics are mathematically driven analysis techniques on large and varied data sets to uncover hidden patterns and trends. We may create de-identified or anonymous data from PII by removing data components (e.g., name, email address, or linkable tracking ID) that makes the data personally identifiable to you or through obfuscation or through other means. Our use of de-identified or anonymized data is not subject to GDPR or this Privacy Policy.

Analytics are used to, for example:

  * Conduct market research and carry out research and statistical analysis including to monitor how members use our networks, products and services;
  * Frame our marketing campaigns and personalization efforts; and
  * Provide reports to third parties (such reports do not contain information which may identify you as an individual).

**8\. How We Share Your Personal Information**

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

  1. Our subsidiaries and corporate affiliates, including Conquer Cancer, CancerLinQ, ASCO Association, and QOPI Certification Program;
  2. Partners, suppliers, vendors, and agents involved in developing or delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used, or the benefits attendant to those products and services (e.g., member benefits);
  3. Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, ASCO or its affiliates;
  4. Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organizations, courts or other public authorities if we must, or are authorized to by law; and
  5. A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

  1. _Promotional Offers from ASCO and Third Parties_

When you register, you may be asked whether you want to receive special announcements and future communications by email. If you check “yes” (or the equivalent) but change your mind at any time in the future and no longer wish to receive correspondence by email, you will be able to opt-out of these services. See  Section 10, “Your rights and User Restrictions”, below.

  2. _Cookies_

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser Cookies, delete Cookies after a time, or alert you when Cookies are being sent. Your browser can be set to reject all Cookies and you can clear Cookies at any time. If you disable or refuse Cookies, then some parts of the Website may not function properly or may be inaccessible. Remember, Cookie settings may be specific to your browser and device.  Various third parties provide additional tools to assist you in managing your own preferences regarding Cookies and digital advertising. We also enable a Cookie consent manager to help you understand what Cookies operate on our site and make informed choices about use of Cookies on our Website. See _Use of Third Party Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies._

  3. Surveys

We occasionally survey visitors to our Website. Survey responses are used in aggregated, de-identified form to help us understand the needs of our visitors so that we can improve our site. The information may be shared on a de-identified and/or aggregated basis with third parties with whom we have a business relationship. While you may always decline to share personal information, if survey respondents provide personal information (e.g., personal email) in a survey, it is shared only with those people who need to see it to respond to the question or request, or with third parties who perform data management services for our Website, product or service. Those third parties have agreed to keep all data from surveys confidential.

  4. IP addresses

The Web server automatically collects the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computers and devices that access our Website. By itself, an IP address merely indicates which computer or device sent a query, which is not PII. Only when correlated with information like user logs, query patterns, and other contextual information do IP addresses potentially convert to PII. Typically, we use this information in aggregate form to understand how our Website or advertisements are being used and to analyze how we can better serve visitors. See Section 13, Glossary, for additional information on PII.

  5. Oncology Career Center

Because the [Oncology Career Center™](http://careercenter.asco.org/) is a career site, it gives job seekers the option of posting their resumes to our database. There are two ways to post a resume.

  1. _Non-Searchable Submission_

You can store your resume in our database but elect to exclude your resume from searches by potential employers. Excluding your resume from database searches means that you can use it to apply for and respond to individual job postings, but employers will not have the ability to search it.

  1. _Searchable Submission_

You will have the option to allow your resume to be searchable by potential employers. Selecting this option permits all parties with access to our searchable resume database to have access to your resume.You may remove your resume from the database and change the status of the resume from searchable to non-searchable, and vice-versa, at any time by updating your profile page on the Oncology Career Center™. 

We cannot and do not guarantee that third parties will not, without our or your consent, gain access to our resume database. You hereby expressly: (a) acknowledge that registered employers and other third parties who gain access to the database with or without our or your consent may retain a copy of your resume, even if you subsequently change the status to non-searchable; and, (b) agree that in no event shall ASCO be responsible or liable for the retention, use, duplication, distribution, or privacy of resumes in these instances.

  6. Event Management

ASCO also uses certain data elements to conduct event management, event data services, and for crime prevention efforts. These use cases include:

  * Sharing with event co-sponsors
  * Sharing with third parties involved in the event process (e.g., hotel booking companies)
  * Potentially sharing with exhibitors at the event through badge scanning onsite at the event. You would physically present your badge for scanning. Attendee Lists and Exhibitor Email applications allow event exhibitors to send you email/direct mail. These applications generally do not allow exhibitors direct access to your contact information.
  * Collecting information concerning compliance with our event policies.
  * When you visit our premises or events, we may also collect information about you on CCTV as part of our security and crime prevention measures

Once your data has been shared with a third party, ASCO no longer has direct control over that information, but we require our Event related vendors to agree to follow applicable law including, where applicable, GDPR.

**9\. Keeping Your Personal Information Secure**

Access to data and technology relating to user information is password-protected and limited to authorized personnel and those vendors that require access to the information in order to furnish services to ASCO and our customers. In addition, ASCO uses industry standard technology to keep users’ information secure while residing on ASCO’s servers. We have specialized security teams who regularly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, accidental loss, disclosure, or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as e-mails) are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may go through several countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the Internet.  We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorized access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

**We will never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication**. You are responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our Website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. Please be sure to read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.  The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.  **Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies.**

**10\. Your Rights and User Restrictions**

  1. _Your California Privacy Rights_

ASCO is a non-profit organization.  California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of our Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send us an email to [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org) or write us at American Society of Clinical Oncology, Inc., 2318 Mill Road, Suite 800, Alexandria, Virginia 22314, Attn: Privacy or Security Officer.

  2. _Right to Correct Personal Data_

You have the right to have information held about you corrected if it is not accurate. If what we hold on you needs updating, or you think it may be inaccurate, please contact our **ASCO Customer Services** team:

Monday–Friday, 8:30am–5:00pm (ET)

2318 Mill Road, Suite 800  
Alexandria, VA 22314

E: [customerservice@asco.org](mailto:customerservice@asco.org)

P: 888-282-2552, 703-299-0158

  1. _Right to Access Personal Data_

You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that ASCO holds about you. To make this request as an individual or an authorized third party, you can contact our ASCO Customer Services Team at the above-referenced contact information.

  1. _Right to Object to Use of Personal Data_

You have the right, in certain circumstances, to object to ASCO processing your personal information.  If you have questions about this right, please contact our ASCO Customer Services Team at the above-referenced contact information.

  1. _To Opt-Out of Marketing Messages_

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from ASCO, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (e.g., email, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

  * Contact our ASCO Customer Services Team

Monday–Friday, 8:30am–5:00pm (ET)

2318 Mill Road, Suite 800

Alexandria, VA 22314

E: [customerservice@asco.org](mailto:customerservice@asco.org)

P: 888-282-2552, 703-299-0158

  * Click the link at the end of a marketing email to unsubscribe from that type of communication;
  * Use the Email Subscriptions link within an e-mail to access the appropriate preference center, and update your preferences there;
  * Log in to your [ASCO.org profile](http://profile.asco.org/) and select "Manage Email Subscription," to control those communications sent directly by ASCO;
  * Visit the Customer Preference Center and revise your selections; or
  * Send us an email at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org).

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, other communications from us regarding transactions you undertake with us, or messages that we have another lawful basis for sending. You may continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).  If you do not wish to receive personalized marketing, or you subsequently change your mind, email [customerservice@asco.org](mailto:customerservice@asco.org). 

Please recognize that Third-Party Managed Pages (and their products and services) may have their own preference centers for communications with you relating to those specific products and services (e.g., our Journal subscriptions or MyConnection forums). If any questions arise, contact us at [customerservice@asco.org](mailto:customerservice@asco.org) or [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org) so that we can discuss your preferences.

  1. _How to Lodge a Complaint_

If you want to contact us about any of your rights or complain about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team or email us at [customerservice@asco.org](mailto:customerservice@asco.org) or [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org).

  1. _Right to restrict use of your data_  
If you feel data we hold on you should not be processed in a particular way or for a particular purpose, please contact our Customer Services team to discuss your rights. In certain circumstances you will have the right to ask us to restrict processing.
  2. _Right to erasure_  
ASCO strives to only process and retain your data for as long as we need to. In certain circumstances you have the right to request that we erase personal data of yours that we hold. If you feel that we are retaining your data longer than we need, it is worth first checking that your contract with ASCO has been terminated, which you can do with Customer Services. If your contract with ASCO has been terminated, then we may still have lawful grounds to process your personal data.
  3. _ASCO Restrictions: Children Under the Age of 13_

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age.  No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on our Website. We do not knowingly collect PII from children under the age of 13. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org).

**11\. How to Contact ASCO**

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can direct your question to the Privacy or Security Officers at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:Privacy@asco.org), or you can contact us at [(+ 001) 571-483-1300](tel:+0015714831300).If you would like to mail us by post directly, send it marked to the “Chief Privacy Officer” at 2318 Mill Road, Suite 800, VA, 22314, USA. Please note, some of these rights such as the right to data portability and right to restriction, apply from 25 May 2018.

**12\. International Users**

ASCO and the Website is based in the United States and, regardless of where you access the Website, the information collected as part of that use will be transferred to and maintained on servers located in the United States. Any information we obtain about you will be stored in accordance with U.S. privacy laws, regulations, and standards, which may not be equivalent to the laws in your country of residence. By using the Website, you consent to this collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the United States in accordance with the foregoing.

If you are an International User, the GDPR (and related international regulations) requires ASCO to inform you of its use of automated decision-making tools.  ASCO uses various tools, such as Google Analytics® and [Adobe Analytics Cloud](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/marketing-cloud.html), to track your online activities to provide you with tailored advertising.  You have the right not to decline decisions based solely on automated processing, including profiling.

**13\. Glossary**

**Cookie (or browser cookie)**. A small data file that is stored on the computer you use to view a website. Cookies are placed by that site (“ **first party** ”) or by a third party with a presence on the site (“ **third party** ”), such as an advertiser using a Web Beacon, and are generally accessed only by the party or site that placed the Cookie on the computer. Cookies may contain pieces of PII. Cookies often are used to make the site easier to use. For example, if you check a box to ask that we store your Username on your computer so that you don’t have to enter it each time you visit the site, that information is stored in a Cookie on your computer. Cookies may be persistent (saved on your device even after you close your Browser) or non-persistent (deleted when you close your Browser). Cookies may be “essential” for the use of a website (e.g., session-id cookies, authentication cookies, or user centric security cookies), or “non-essential” e.g., third-party advertising cookies or other tracking cookies. As used in this Privacy Policy, the term “Cookies” also refers to Web Beacons and Pixels and other tracking technologies.

**Non-Personal Information (“NPI”)**. Information that may relate to an individual but does not by itself identify that individual. For example, browser information is Non-Personal Information, as is information such as gender, age, city, and physical location, when not linked with other PII.  NPI may be “re-identified” through certain processes by linking it to PII relating to the same individual.

**Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”)**. Any representation of information that permits the identity of an individual to whom the information applies to be reasonably inferred by either direct or indirect means. Further, PII is defined as information: (i) that directly identifies an individual (e.g., name, address, SSN or other identifying number or code, telephone number, email address, etc.) or (ii) by which an organization intends to identify specific individuals in conjunction with other data elements, i.e., indirect identification. (These data elements may include a combination of gender, race, birth date, geographic indicator, ASCO Member ID and/or other descriptors). Additionally, information permitting the physical or online contacting of a specific individual is the same as PII. This information can be maintained any form. For the purposes of GDPR, PII includes personal data as defined by GDPR.

**Web Beacons** or **Pixels** (also often referred to as “clear GIFs,” “pixel tags,” “1-by-1 GIFs,” “Single-Pixel GIFs,” “1 x 1 Pixels” or “clear Pixels”). Pages of the website and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons that permit us and/or third parties to collect Web Information during your visit to the Website. For example, Web Beacons may be used to count the number of users who have visited a page or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity). Web Beacons send information back to their home server (which can belong to the host site, a network advertiser, or some other third party) from the users’ Browser, such as the IP address, the URL of the page on which the beacon is located, the type of Browser that is accessing the site, and information stored in any Cookies on the users’ computer previously placed by that server. Web Beacons can also be used to place a Cookie on the users’ Browser. Third parties who provide us with web beacons or pixels may have the ability to link the information they collect about you when you use the Website with other information they collect about you elsewhere on the Internet, including but not limited to your PII or information about the device you are using.  

**Website**. Collectively, the [ASCO website](http://www.asco.org/), the [Cancer.Net](https://www.cancer.net/) website, the [ASCO Journals](https://ascopubs.org/) websites, the [Oncology Career Center™](http://careercenter.asco.org/) website, [ASCO Practice Central](https://practice.asco.org/), the [ASCO eLearning](https://elearning.asco.org/) website, the [_ASCO Connection_](https://connection.asco.org/) website, the [ASCO Photo Gallery](http://photos.asco.org/), the [TAPUR Study](http://www.tapur.org/) website, the [ASCO Meeting Library](https://meetinglibrary.asco.org/) website, the ASCO in Action website, the [ASCO Volunteer Portal](http://volunteer.asco.org/), [certain state affiliate](https://myaffiliates.asco.org/home) websites, meeting microsites, and any other online functionalities or services included in the websites operated by ASCO, but excluding our mobile applications. For the avoidance of doubt, the Website specifically includes any website owned or operated by ASCO on which this Privacy Policy is posted.
